#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/valerie-c-a35b2b52 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Healthcare

Hospitals

Healthcare Management

### Honors-Awards

Clinical Excellence Award

Spirit and Art of Nursing Award

# Valerie Collins MBA, MSN, APRN, FNP-C

RN at Saint Luke's Community Hospital

Kansas City, Missouri Area

## Summary

I possess years of extensive clinical and leadership experience.

I have provided direct patient care, which has taught me to be sensitive to the needs and challenges that face our complex patient population. I have also served in leadership roles and have acquired skills of planning, delegation and encouraging productivity.

## Experience

Saint Luke's Community Hospital RN January 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Tandem Hospital Partners, LLC Staff RN February 2018 - Present (2 years 5 months) Leawood, Kansas

Independent Beachbody Coach Coach March 2015 - Present (5 years 4 months)

Centerpoint Medical Center of Independence, LLC Travel Registered Nurse December 2016 - June 2017 (7 months)

Mount Sinai Beth Israel
Shift Administrator
September 2016 - December 2016 (4 months)
10 Nathan D Perlman Pl, New York, NY 10003

I assume administrative responsibility for the management of multiple departments while unit managers and directors are off shift.

Portsmouth Regional Hospital Travel RN June 2016 - September 2016 (4 months) Portsmouth, New Hampshire

BayCare Health System
Travel RN ICU
February 2016 - June 2016 (5 months)

Tampa/St. Petersburg, Florida Area

Northwest Medical Center
Travel RN Stepdown
November 2015 - February 2016 (4 months)

Cooper County Memorial Hospital Travel RN August 2015 - November 2015 (4 months)

Froedtert West Bend Health Center Travel Nurse Administrative Supervisor May 2015 - August 2015 (4 months) West Bend, Wisconsin

Assumes responsibility of Nursing Administrator for the assigned shift and assumes responsibility for other hospital departments in the absence of their

Supervise patient care activities, significant patient care issues and acts to advocate in patients interest according to hospital policy

Coordinates staffing needs with Directors / Managers and monitors unit staffing to ensure that patient acuity levels, census and ratios are met

Mountain Vista Medical Center Travel RN ICU January 2015 - April 2015 (4 months)

Methodist Healthcare System Travel RN Stepdown October 2014 - January 2015 (4 months) San Antonio, Texas

Travel RN -IMCU ISCU

leaders.

## Children's Hospitals and Clinics of Minnesota Travel RN (House Supervisor) June 2014 - September 2014 (4 months)

minneapolis, minnesota and st paul, minnesota

Saint Luke's Health System RN House Supervisor

January 2006 - May 2014 (8 years 5 months)

- •Oversees and coordinates patient care activities throughout the hospital
- Directs professional and non-professional nursing personnel;
- •Coordinates patient care activities with staff and physicians
- •Resolves quality of care concerns •Serves as resource for complex patient care situations.
- •Coordinates staffing for oncoming shift/s based on patient census, care needs, and staff competency
- •Communicates and collaborates with directors and staff to ensure staffing consistent with established unit staffing plans
- •Directs appropriate response to, emergent, life threatening, or safety situations
- •Responds to and provides direction for all hospital codes/alerts
- •Acts the incident commander in the event of a hospital wide disaster until the arrival of the administrator on-call
- •Acts to resolve staff, patient and visitor safety concerns.
- •Collaborates with appropriate agencies, care providers, and other staff for patient transfers to ensure patient safety and compliance with hospital policies and external regulations
- coordinates with Organ
- •Coordinates/directs total hospital operations (in absence of directors and/or administration) Contacts on-call personnel
- •Procures supplies, medical records, etc. as needed
- Handles customer complaints per hospital policy

Graceland University
Clinical Adjunct Faculty
2011 - January 2012 (1 year)

- •Participated in clinical orientation sessions, course coordination meetings and special meetings relative to course.
- •Selects student clinical assignments that were appropriate to course content/ clinical objectives.
- •Evaluated and informed students of their performance.

- •Maintained anecdotal notes for students, documenting performance and made recommendations to the student.
- •Confered with each student at the completion of a clinical rotation as a component of the clinical performance evaluation process.
- •Evaluated students' written assignments related to clinical laboratory experience and returns same to students within a reasonable time.
- •Supported policies as stated in the Course Manual
- •Supervised patient care according to:
- a. Clinical Nursing Policies, and
- b. Student's abilities
- •Demonstrated and encouraged critical thinking skills.
- •Completed and submitted end-of-course materials related to student performance.

#### Carondelet Health

RN Resource Team

August 2000 - February 2006 (5 years 7 months)

Cross trained to float to clinical areas on the St Joseph Medical Center campus: Medicine, Cardiopulmonary, Surgical, Ortho, ICU, Oncology, Stepdown, CCU, Renal, Rehab and Short Stay.

- •Safely, therapeutically and efficiently cared for groups of patients.
- •Utilized information from a variety of sources and assessed, planned, implemented, identified outcomes as well as evaluated patients plan of care.

#### **AMN Healthcare**

**RN Travel Nurse** 

December 1997 - June 2000 (2 years 7 months)

Multiple locations

Traveled to various facilities across the US, specializing in delivery of care to Bone Marrow Transplant and Hematology Oncology patients. Facilities included:

Baptist East Hospital, Memphis, TN

Johns Hopkins Hospital, Baltimore, MD (two tours)

Kansas University Hospital, Kansas City, KS

University of Cincinnati Hospital, Cincinnati, OH

Mayo Clinic Hospital, Phoenix, AZ

Skills included:

interventions

•Knowledgeable on cancer therapy modalities: Radiation therapy
Brachytherapy Radiopharmaceutical •Delivery of care to patients with surgical

- Biotherapy Chemotherapy
- Evaluation of pertinent patient lab data
- Calculation of body surface area
- Care of patient with extravasion
- Administration of Chemotherapy and Blood Products
- Management of cytoxic spills
- ·Handling of cytoxic agents
- •Handling of body fluids post chemo
- •Utilized information from a variety of sources and assessed, planned, implemented, identified outcomes as well as evaluated patients plan of care.

# Education

Maryville University of Saint Louis
Studies Post Masters Family Nurse Practitioner, Family Practice Nurse/
Nursing · (2017 - 2019)

University of Mary

MSN/Master of Business Administration (MBA), Nursing Administration/ Healthcare · (2009 - 2011)

Central Methodist University-College of Liberal Arts & Sciences Nursing, Registered Nurse · (1987)